dwp.gov.uk 2013-12-31

# Privacy Policy - DWP

This page explains the privacy policy for the Department for Work and Pensions and how we will use and protect any information we collect about you when you visit this website.

  * How DWP collects and uses information
  * The Data Protection Act
  * Email
  * Cookies
  * Links to other websites
  * Changes to this privacy policy

## How DWP collects and uses information 

The Department for Work and Pensions collects information to deal with social security (including Housing Benefit, Council Tax Reduction schemes and Local Welfare Provision), child support, vaccine damage, employment and training, promoting financial planning for retirement, and policy relating to occupational and personal pension schemes. The information we collect about you depends on the reason for your business with us, but we may use the information for any of these purposes.

To help people receive help and support through the government's welfare reforms the department will share information for an increasing number of welfare services. The sorts of services that this refers to are diverse but include:

  * services to help people with particular difficulties such as the government's Troubled Families Programme
  * schemes to help people into work or to obtain better skills and training to assist in obtaining work, for example through Get Britain Working initiatives
  * services that support people with independent living: this would include a range of services such as entitlement to a Blue Badge
  * services that provide domiciliary and respite care.

We may check information about you with other information we have. We may get information about you from other people and certain other organisations. We may give information to certain other organisations, as the law allows, to:

  * check the accuracy of information 
  * prevent or detect crime 
  * protect public funds in other ways 
  * use in research or statistics. 

These other organisations include other government departments, local authorities, and private-sector bodies such as banks and organisations that may lend you money. We will not give information about you to anyone outside our department unless the law allows us to.

top of page

## The Data Protection Act

The Department for Work and Pensions is the Data Controller for the purposes of the Data Protection Act. Our website does not enable our visitors to communicate with other visitors or for them to post information to be accessed by others.

Our [personal information charter](https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/department-for-work-pensions/about/personal-information-charter) (GOV.UK) explains:  

  * how we collect and use personal information 
  * how to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you.

top of page

## Email

Internet email is a way of making general enquiries but it is not a secure way to send personal information. DWP regrets that it cannot deal with specific enquiries by email. If you send us an email, we may keep a copy for reference and audit purposes.

top of page

## Cookies

We want our services to be easy, useful and reliable. For services delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These small files are known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.

These pieces of information are used to improve services by, for example:

  * enabling a service to recognise your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task
  * recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested
  * measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast.

You can manage cookies yourself and learn more about them on GOV.UK.

If you delete cookies or you set your browser not to accept cookies, you will not be able to use some of our services.

  * How we use cookies

You can manage cookies yourself and learn more about them on GOV.UK.

  * [Internet browser cookies – what they are and how to manage them](https://www.gov.uk/support/cookies) (GOV.UK)

top of page

## Links to other websites

The DWP website contains links to other sites. This privacy policy applies only to the DWP site. When you move to another website, you will need to read the privacy statement of that site.

top of page

## Changes to this privacy policy

If this privacy policy changes, we will update this page. Check this page to make sure you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it and the circumstances we may share it with other organisations.

top of page
